Breno Jones Agrelli

Recife, Pernambuco, Brazil



bjagrelli@gmail.com



+5581997049995



linkedin.com/in/bjagrelli

Summary

I am Data Engineer with industry experience in ETL, data migration and Big Data solutions. I specialize in Python and SQL and have professional experience working with Spark and Databricks. I also have experience working with different cloud providers, such as GCP and Azure. In the past I worked with data analysis and have experience with data modelling, data warehousing and reporting with tools such as QlikSense and PowerBI.

I have a bachelor's degree (BSc) in Civil Engineering and I can state that this background gave me various tools to tackle different problems with analytical thinking and decision making to provide efficient outcomes.

Experience

Software Engineering Senior Analyst

Accenture Brasil

Sep 2022 - Present (6 months)

I currently work on a project for a multinational health provider company.

(Aug/2022 - Now): I operate on a small squad developing data engineering solutions to a BI project.

- Assisted with the data platform blueprint and design, encompassing the relevant data platform components. Collaborates with the Integration Architects and Data Architects to ensure cohesive integration between systems and data models.
- Developed batch and streaming ETL pipelines using Azure Synapse Analytics and Azure Databricks to ingest, transform and integrate data from different sources (Relational databases, APIs and flat files).
- Assisted in Data Modeling for the creation of fact and dimension tables for a dashboard.
- Assisted in the implementation of Databricks' Unity Catalog.

Technologies: Azure Databricks, SQL, Python, Azure Synapse Analytics, Azure DevOps.

Software Engineering Analyst

Accenture Brasil

Jul 2021 - Sep 2022 (1 year 3 months)

I have worked in three different projects for major telecom companies in Brazil.

(Jul/2021 - Apr/2022): Two data migration projects for a major telecom company in Brazil.

- Developed ETL pipelines in PL/SQL and Azure Data Factory to migrate data from an on-premises Oracle database to a cloud-based Oracle database with a different architecture in Azure. I alseo automatized reporting tools for internal use with Python and Bash.
- Most challenging task was to clean, standardize, correct and validate addresses to fit in the new database architecture.

Technologies: SQL, Python, Git, Azure Data Factory, Bash.

(Apr/2022 - Aug/2022): Big Data project for another big telecom company.

- Built streaming and batch ETL and ELT pipelines for an e-commerce. Data would come in json and csv formats and should be transformed and loaded into BigQuery.
- Responsible for the implementation of the Data Lifecyle Management (DLM).

Technologies: Python, Apache Spark, Delta Lake, Google Cloud Storage, BigQuery, Bash, Git.

Analista de dados

Ortoestética

Dec 2019 - Jul 2021 (1 year 8 months)

On this position I improved internal reports and created spreadsheets, compiling metrics to create dashboards that help managers access and interact with information easily. I also work creating tools to help with the franchise expansion and implementation. I use mostly QlikSense and Google Sheets on these tasks.

Education

Universidade de Pernambuco

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), Engenharia Civil 2011 - 2019

TU/e Eindhoven University of Technology

Graduação Sanduíche, Engenharia Civil 2014 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

- Accademia Accenture | Data Engineer Gama Academy
- **Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals** Microsoft
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Amazon Web Services (AWS)
 Issued Aug 2021 Expires Aug 2024
- Academy Accreditation Databricks Lakehouse Fundamentals Databricks Issued Feb 2023 Expires Feb 2024 67577929

Skills

Python • SQL • Data Engineering • Azure Databricks • Bash • Git • Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) • Microsoft Azure • Data Lakes • Data Warehousing